{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Who invented the Ruby language?",
      "correctAnswer": "Yukihiro Matsumoto",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "Steve Jobs",
        "Bill Gates"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the highest level in the object model?",
      "correctAnswer": "BasicObject",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "Object",
        "PrimitiveObject"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which core object includes the Kernel module?",
      "correctAnswer": "Object",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "BasicObject",
        "PopcornObject"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Does String include the Enumerable module?",
      "correctAnswer": "No",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "Yes"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What happens when a value becomes too big for Fixnum?",
      "correctAnswer": "It is automatically converted to a Bignum.",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "It turns into a Float",
        "It automatically truncates"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In what order are the values of a hash iterated?",
      "correctAnswer": "The order in which they were inserted.",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "The order of their size",
        "The order of the keys"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are two uses of ranges?",
      "correctAnswer": "comparison and iteration",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "collection and comparision",
        "iteration and collection"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is not a use of the splat operator?",
      "correctAnswer": "Product of two arrays",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "Explode or expand the elements of an array.",
        "Collect arguments of a parameter list into an array."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Does a while block define a new scope?",
      "correctAnswer": "No",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "Yes"
      ]

    },
    {
      "question": "Does the case statement in Ruby have fall-through behavior?",
      "correctAnswer": "No",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "Yes"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the meaning of self?",
      "correctAnswer": "The current object.",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "The user's conscience",
        "The current context"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does a bang (or exclamation point) at the end of a method signify?",
      "correctAnswer": "A mutation on the receiver object",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "A loud operation",
        "Ruby is excited to execute the method"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "When might you explicitly use the return statement?",
      "correctAnswer": "To return from a method prematurely",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "When the Ruby gets bored of executing",
        "When the method causes a stack overflow"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a singleton method?",
      "correctAnswer": "A method that is available only on a single object",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "A method that wants to be alone",
        "A method that can be executed only once"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a factory method?",
      "correctAnswer": "An initialization method that creates specialized instances of a class.",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "A method that is created by the Ruby Environment",
        "A method that was born in the Industrial Revolution Era"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an IO object?",
      "correctAnswer": "An object that can be used for file data transfer.",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "An object that can be used for bulk data deletion",
        "There's no such thing"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "If more than one version of a Gem is installed, which version will be used?",
      "correctAnswer": "The Gem with the highest version number.",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "The Gem that was installed first",
        "Neither, Ruby hates merge conflicts just as much as you do"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What error is raised if a method is passed the wrong number of arguments?",
      "correctAnswer": "ArgumentError",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "IOError",
        "404 Error"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What error is raised if method name resolution fails?",
      "correctAnswer": "NoMethodError",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "YesMethodError",
        "MaybeMethodError"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the difference between \"puts\" and \"print\"?",
      "correctAnswer": "puts appends a newline character to the output",
      "tags": "Ruby",
      "wrongAnswer": [
        "puts is more efficient",
        "Ruby likes puts more than print"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does CSS stand for?",
      "correctAnswer": "Cascading Style Sheets",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "Common Style Selectors",
        "Creative Style Sheets"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which property is used to change the background color?",
      "correctAnswer": "background-color",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "background-style",
        "apply-color"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which CSS property is used to change the text color of an element?",
      "correctAnswer": "color",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "text-color",
        "change-color"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which CSS property controls the text size?",
      "correctAnswer": "font-size",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "change-size",
        "text-size"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which property is used to change the font of an element?",
      "correctAnswer": "font-family",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "font-style",
        "apply-font"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which property is responsible for bolding a text element?",
      "correctAnswer": "font-weight",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "text-boldness",
        "text-adjust"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which property is used to adjust the outer spacing of an element?",
      "correctAnswer": "margin",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "padding",
        "border"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "When using the padding property, are you allowed to use negative values?",
      "correctAnswer": "No",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "Yes"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following CSS properties do not exist?",
      "correctAnswer": "text-opacity",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "position",
        "box-sizing"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "True or false: monospace is a generic font family",
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "False"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following a valid supported color name?",
      "correctAnswer": "Aquamarine",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "Coffee",
        "Tangerine"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which property would you use to remove or add underlines?",
      "correctAnswer": "text-decoration",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "underline-status",
        "text-underline"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an not a valid position value?",
      "correctAnswer": "temporary",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "static",
        "sticky"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which display property is used to hide elements?",
      "correctAnswer": "none",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "contents",
        "minimize"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which selector is used to select all immediate elements below an element?",
      "correctAnswer": "child selector",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "all-below",
        "next"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an example of a pseudo-class?",
      "correctAnswer": "hover",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "body",
        "footer"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which property would you use to adjust capitalization for text?",
      "correctAnswer": "text-transform",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "capitalize",
        "text-case"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "What would happen if the opacity of an element was set to 0?",
      "correctAnswer": "the element would not be displayed on screen",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "the element would be deleted",
        "nothing"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following lengths units are not valid in CSS?",
      "correctAnswer": "meter",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "millimeter",
        "pica"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which property would you use to round the corners of an element??",
      "correct_answer": "border-radius",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "roundness",
        "element-smooth"
      ],
      "tags": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does HTML stand for?",
      "correctAnswer": "Hypertext Markup Language",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "Hotmail ",
        "How To Make Language"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "True or false: all HTML documents must start with a document type declaration",
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "False"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the 'p' tag used for?",
      "correctAnswer": "creating a paragraph",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "creating a partition",
        "creating a new page"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of tag is used to define an HTML link?",
      "correctAnswer": "anchor tag",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "link tag",
        "url tag"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not an attribute of an image tag?",
      "correctAnswer": "image-border",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "alternative text",
        "source file"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the <ul> tag stand for?",
      "correctAnswer": "unordered list",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "underline",
        "unused link"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following will produce the largest default heading font?",
      "correctAnswer": "h1",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "h2",
        "h3"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "True or false: All HTML elements must close with an ending tag.",
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "True"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does href refer to?",
      "correctAnswer": "the URL or web address for a link",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "image file path",
        "HTML reference"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many default headings are defined in HTML?",
      "correctAnswer": "6",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "3",
        "5"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HTML element is metadata stored in?",
      "correctAnswer": "head element",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "body element",
        "footer element"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "True or false: a web browser recognizes extra white space within a paragraph tag",
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "True"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which tag is used to preserve both spaces and line breaks?",
      "correctAnswer": "pre tag",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "p tag",
        "spaces tag"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "What attribute allows you to use in-line CSS on an HTML element?",
      "correctAnswer": "style",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "in-line CSS",
        "CSS-active"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "What HTML defines removed or strike-through text?",
      "correctAnswer": "del",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "cross-out",
        "strike-through"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "True or false: You can only use text as links in HTML?",
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "True"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the default display marking for a list item?",
      "correctAnswer": "bullet point",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "dash",
        "none"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a valid block element?",
      "correctAnswer": "image element",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "list element",
        "header element"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a valid inline element?",
      "correctAnswer": "script",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "article",
        "figure"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which tag defines a block-level section in a document?",
      "correct_answer": "div",
      "wrongAnswer":[
        "span",
        "canvas"
      ],
      "tags": "HTML"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company created JavaScript?",
        "correctAnswer": "Oracle",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "Netscape",
            "Krispy Kreme"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many days did it take Brendan Eich to create JavaScript?",
        "correctAnswer": "10 days",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "He wasn't the creator",
            "Forever"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What was JavaScript originally called?",
        "correctAnswer": "Mocha",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "Frappucino",
            "EcmaScript"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False? JavaScript is dynamically typed.",
        "correctAnswer": "True",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False? Null is an object.",
        "correctAnswer": "False",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "True",
            "null"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "5 divided by 0 is equal to which of the following?",
        "correctAnswer": "Infinity",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "Undefined",
            "A pretty big number"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a JavaScript event?",
        "correctAnswer": "onUnload",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "onJump",
            "onLinkClick"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "JavaScript is a subset of Java",
        "correctAnswer": "Hell no!",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "Hell yes!"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False? Global variables are not created automatically in Strict Mode.",
        "correctAnswer": "True",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "False",
            "What is Strict Mode?"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Can we equate two arrays in JavaScript?",
        "correctAnswer": "Yes",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "No"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False? JavaScript is weird.",
        "correctAnswer": "True",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": []
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call JavaScript without any additional frameworks or libraries?",
        "correctAnswer": "Vanilla",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
          "Plain JavaScript",
          "Chocolate JavaScript"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does each JavaScript statement need to end with?",
        "correctAnswer": "semicolon",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
          "period",
          "question mark"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most common case used in JavaScript?",
        "correctAnswer": "Lower Camel Case",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
          "Underscore",
          "Hyphens"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What data type do you get when you add a Number and String?",
        "correctAnswer": "String",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
          "Number",
          "Stringy Number"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a valid data type?",
        "correctAnswer": "Array",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
          "Number",
          "String"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many basic data types are there in JavaScript?",
        "correctAnswer": "7",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
          "5",
          "10"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What data type contains the values true and false?",
        "correctAnswer": "Boolean",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
          "Binary",
          "Flag"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call a block of code designed to perform a particular task?",
        "correctAnswer": "Function",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
          "Program",
          "Method"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does 'this' refer to in a function definition?",
        "correctAnswer": "The owner of the function",
        "tags": "JavaScript",
        "wrongAnswer": [
          "A confusing question",
          "Not 'that'"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company developed SQL?",
        "correctAnswer": "IBM",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "Oracle",
            "Microsoft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False? A Primary Key is required for a table.",
        "correctAnswer": "False",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "True"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which SQL statement is used to extract data from a database?",
        "correctAnswer": "SELECT",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "GET",
            "EXTRACT"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a SQL statement?",
        "correctAnswer": "DESTROY TABLE",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "DELETE",
            "DROP TABLE"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The S in SQL stands for which of the following?",
        "correctAnswer": "Structured",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "Standardized",
            "Sequential"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the underscore represent in a LIKE statement?",
        "correctAnswer": "Single Character",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "Wildcard Character",
            "Lowercase Character"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False? The ORDER BY statement is executed before the GROUP BY statement.",
        "correctAnswer": "False",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "True"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The JOIN statement defaults to which of the following?",
        "correctAnswer": "INNER JOIN",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "LEFT JOIN",
            "FULL JOIN"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which SQL statement is used to create an alias?",
        "correctAnswer": "AS",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "ALIAS",
            "CREATE"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "An alias cannot be made for which of the following?",
        "correctAnswer": "Database",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "Table",
            "Column"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a SQL function?",
        "correctAnswer": "MID",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "MIN",
            "MAX"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Is it true that SQL can only be used for relational databases?",
        "correctAnswer": "Yes",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "No"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a SQL operator?",
        "correctAnswer": "NOT",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "NOR",
            "NIL"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False? UNION ALL is a SQL operator.",
        "correctAnswer": "True",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The EXISTS operator checks for which of the following?",
        "correctAnswer": "Existence of a record in a subquery",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "Existence of a database given a parameter"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a SQL function?",
        "correctAnswer": "NOTNULL",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "ISNULL",
            "IFNULL"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which SQL statement is used to return only different values?",
        "correctAnswer": "SELECT DISTINCT",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "SELECT UNIQUE",
            "SELECT DIFFERENT"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which SQL keyword is used to sort the result?",
        "correctAnswer": "ORDER BY",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "SORT BY",
            "SORT"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is not a DDL statement?",
        "correctAnswer": "Delete",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "Truncate",
            "Alter"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which operator is used to select values within a range?",
        "correctAnswer": "BETWEEN",
        "tags": "SQL",
        "wrongAnswer": [
            "WITHIN",
            "RANGE"
        ]
    }
  ]
}
